Sangita B K

Arlington, TX 76010 | 469.810.4608 | sangitabk391@gmail.com | www.linkedin.com/in/sangitabk | https://sangitabk.github.io | https://github.com/sangitabk

SUMMARY

Highly collaborative problem solver with 1 year plus of diversified experience in research, product development, project management, and analysis on the lookout for a full-time opportunity in a fast-paced environment upon graduation. Quick learner and extremely good at picking up new things.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas At Arlington, Arlington, Texas

Aug 2018 - May 2021

Bachelor of Engineering - Biomedical Engineering, GPA: 3.61/4

El Centro College, Dallas, Texas Associates of Science, GPA: 3.60/4 Jan 2017 - May 2018

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

Computer Skills: MATLAB, Solid Works, LabVIEW, Microsoft Office Skills, Minitab, DSI Studio, FSL, FreeSurfer Technical Skills: Digital Technology, Digital Bio-Signal Processing, Circuit Analysis, Six Sigma Methodology Competencies: Problem Solving, Decision Making, Project Management, Interpersonal Relationship, Teamwork

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Smart Hospital, Arlington, TX (Intern)

(Projected time) Jan 2021 - May 2021

Cook Children's Jane and John Justin Neurosciences Center, Fort Worth, TX Research Assistant

Nov 2020 - Present

Analyze the Diffusion imaging tensor data, volume, and cortical thickness of the brain of patients in Cook's Children Medical Center using FreeSurfer and FSL.

Radio Frequency & Auto Identification Labs, The University of Texas at Arlington, TX

Jun2020 - Present

- **Undergraduate Research Assistant**
 - Initiated the collection and analysis of data for scientific papers while writing the results for its publication.

Created stimulation on RFID grown brain cells and analyzed its activities using **NEURON Programming**.

Led a group of 5 fellow research assistants planning, coordinating, and supervising the assigned research projects, exercising responsibility and accountability for progress, providing efficient results.

The University of Texas at Arlington Research Institute | NSF (\$224,893), TX **Research Assistant**

Jan 2020 - Aug 2020

- Created wax and silicone molds for prototyping and functional testing of rehab gloves and fabricated digits which include the art inertial measurement sensor to monitor the joint motion.
 - Performed curing procedure on the model for testing and prototyping purpose.
 - Tested the soft robotic glove for the pressure sensitivity of 20mm of Hg in water and air 20 times, which is later used for quantifiable diagnostic.

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCES

Biomedical Engineering Capstone Project

Aug 2020- Present

- Create a biosensor for the detection of the two most common nosocomial bacteria.
- Prepared buffer solution for the pretreatment of the paper pad and assembled the paper strips.
- Prepared the binding assay for the affinity of the antibodies and fluorescence of the gold nanoparticle.

PUBLICATIONS

- Bracey Princess, Sangita B K, Erick Jones, and Felicia Jefferson. "The Impact of Substance Abuse on Pregnant Teens." International Supply Chain Technology Journal 06.09 (2020). Print.
- Weekes, Jalissa, Sangita B K, Erick Jones, Felicia Jefferson, and Zenzeale Hudson. "The Effects of Genetically Modified Crops." International Supply Chain Technology Journal 6.9 (2020). Print.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCES

US Department of State | Fulbright Commission Nepal | World Learning

Jan 2016 - May 2016

Educational and Cultural Ambassador

- Participant in an international program to increase mutual understanding and peaceful relations between The United States and other countries.
- Educated people from 81 nationalities about Nepali culture through various workshops.